— SYEFIRA SHOFA ←

MARKETING ANALYST

CONTACT

(818) 736-1863

sshofa@sandiego.edu

https://www.linkedin.com/in/syefira-shofa/

https://sshofa.github.io

PROFILE

Technical Marketing Analyst with a Mathematics background experienced in the video game, consumer electronics and genealogy industries. Familiar with various marketing channels spanning throughout all parts of the marketing funnel. Adept at developing ETL's, mathematical and statistical modeling, and performance reporting.

SKILLS

Computing

SQL, R, Python

Analytics Tools

Apache Airflow, Apache Spark, GitHub, GitLab, Databricks, AWS Redshift & S3, Tableau, Datorama, Microsoft Power BI

Marketing Channels

Offline TV, Audio, Display & Video, Programmatic, Social, Search, In-Game Communication, Email, Push, SMS

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Georgia Institute of Technology

Masters of Science, Analytics

Anticipated Completion: May 2024

Georgia Institute of Technology

MicroMasters, Analytics: Essential Tools & Methods

University of San Diego

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics

Minors: International Business & Asian Studies

EXPERIENCE

Marketing Analyst

Activision, 2020-Present

- Designed A/B test and conducted statistical modeling to investigate marketing impact on company KPI's
- Explained methodologies used and interpretation of results in lament terms to stakeholders
- Analyzed performance of marketing efforts and worked cross-functionally with stakeholders to implement optimization recommendations
- Owned automated dashboard ETL and partnered with the data visualization team to visualize the data in a simplified manner that still allows for deeper understanding of campaign performance

Associate Marketing Science Manager

OMD, 2019-2020

Account: Apple, Ancestry

- Designed, tested, deployed and optimized automated data process with data coming in from multiple data sources across all media channels on a global scale
- Developed match market test statistical methodology to test effectiveness of new marketing tactic, Recursive Partitioning model to identify best audience grouping for benchmarks, RMarkdown reporting templates for automated reporting, flighting strategy to optimize media allocation throughout the new fiscal year

Analyst

MediaCom, 2018-2019

Account: PlayStation

- Rebuilt the database, optimized the data process and improved naming conventions
- Developed and automated business intelligence dashboards for data visualization and insight generation
- Connected excel to SQL database, allowing internal teams to obtain data in real time and analyze with customized data for reporting